peanutlabs.com 2017-12-09

# Peanut Labs Monetization | Privacy Policy

Peanut Labs Inc. (“Peanut Labs”) is committed to protecting the privacy and confidentiality of your information on our Website [www.peanutlabs.com](http://www.peanutlabs.com/) and on the Peanut Labs platform. As a data collection company, we provide accurate and dependable data to the market research industry. Our services offer respondents the opportunity to take part in market research and express opinions and attitudes regarding a broad range of subjects. Our clients depend on this information to make many decisions that affect the products and services in the marketplace. Any data that we collect for a study is reported only in aggregate, and specific information regarding individuals is never viewed or published. All information gathered either during registration or in supplemental demographic surveys is provided the highest level of security.

**Trans-National Data Flow**

Peanut Labs adheres to the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) guidelines, specifically the Fair Information Practices governing the protection of privacy. This involves the trans-border data flows of personal data. International Data Transfers are defined as the transmission of personal information from one jurisdiction to another. Many jurisdictions, most notably the European Union (EU), place significant restrictions on such transfers. The EU requires that the receiving jurisdiction be judged to have “adequate” data protection practices.

Peanut Labs transfers data between the EU and the U.S. in accordance with standard contractual clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established in third countries (“Model Contract”) pursuant to the Commission Decision 2010/87/EU of 5th February, 2010.

**EU-U.S. Privacy Shield**

Peanut Labs(and its parent company Research Now Group, Inc.) participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Peanut Labs is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s [Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

Peanut Labs is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Peanut Labs complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Peanut Labs is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, [Participant] may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**What We Gather**

Users access the Peanut Labs platform via third-party partner websites (“Partners”), where users have already completed the Partner’s registration process. Any personal information the Partner may have collected as part of the Partner registration process is not shared with Peanut Labs. We do, however, obtain some personal information directly from Users on the Peanut Labs platform during the Peanut Labs registration process that helps to identify the types of studies most in line with a person’s buying habits, interests, or product usage. In order to participate in surveys that are relevant to them, participants need to fill out general consumer information and limited personal information. For instance; if we are looking to conduct a survey among coffee drinkers, we would only choose those persons who indicated in their registration that they drink coffee products. We also ask demographic information (e.g., gender, birth date, household income, and zip or country code). We may require a user’s email address in order to contact the user with reward details upon completing surveys. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which aclient has engaged Peanut Labs, and in some instances, to contact users with reward details. We may share individual User information collected during the Peanut Labs registration process with the Partner from whose site the User is accessing the Peanut Labs platform.

When publishers visit the site [www.peanutlabs.com](http://www.peanutlabs.com/), we collect personal information from them including but not limited to name, email address, bank account number and social security number.

**Information Related to Data Collected through the Peanut Labs Platform**

Peanut Labs collects aggregated information under the direction of its clients and partners.

**Choice**

We collect aggregated information for our clients and partners, if you are a customer of one of our clients or partners and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our clients or partners that use our service, please contact the client or partner that you interact with directly.

**Access to and Retention of Data Controlled by our Clients**

We acknowledge that you have the right to access your personal information. Peanut Labs has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the Peanut Lab’s Client (the data controller). If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

Peanut Labs will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Peanut Labs will retain this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Service Provider, Sub-Processors/Onward Transfer**

Peanut Labs may transfer aggregated information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our clients and partners.

**Information Use and Sharing**

Peanut Labs will never sell nor share the information collected from any individual member with any third parties, except as outlined in this privacy policy.

We use the personal information you provide through our website to respond to your customer service requests and for the purposes of improving the site to serve you better.The information collected through our platform is used only for determining which members are qualified to take market research studies. Information may be shared in aggregate to our clients.

We may also provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as our hosting provider or banking service provider. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us

**Children and Parents**

Peanut Labs’ surveys and website are not designed nor intended for use by children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13. If we discover that we have inadvertently gathered any such information for a child under 13, we will take appropriate steps to delete it. If your child has submitted personal information, and you wish to delete such information, as well as refuse to allow any further collection or use of your child’s information, please contact us at the address provided below. Peanut Labs adheres to the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act.

**Access and Choice**

Upon request Peanut Labs will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information.

If your personal information changes, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove it by emailing us at [support@peanutlabs.com](mailto:support@peanutlabs.com). We will respond to your request to access within a reasonable time frame.

We will retain your personal information and the aggregated information we process for clients and partners, for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Survey and Email Opt-Out Policy**

By filling out a profile, you agree to receive invitations to participate in our Internet surveys. If you would like to discontinue receiving invitations to participate, please e-mail us at [support@peanutlabs.com](mailto:support@peanutlabs.com) and write “Remove Name” in the subject line. If a respondent chooses to formally end their survey participation, all information related to their individual profile will be permanently removed from our database. It can take two (2) to three (3) business days to completely remove the data from all of our records.

We may use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [support@peanutlabs.com](mailto:support@peanutlabs.com).

**Tracking Technologies**

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Peanut Labs and our partners, affiliates, advertisers, research clients, analytics services and service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference) and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We do not link this automatically-collected data to personal information. IP addresses are not tied to personal information. IP addresses are only used to insure the same user does not respond to a survey multiple times.

**Security**

Peanut Labs adheres to strict rules that ensure every aspect of our data is secure, including the aggregated information processed on our platform. Access to all profile information is restricted to a few key personnel in order to prevent the loss, misuse, and unauthorized alteration of the information under our control. When partners enter sensitive information, such as bank account information, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

Our security policies and procedures are reviewed constantly to ensure that we utilize standard technology and internal processes that best protect respondents’ information entrusted to us. All questions are screened to ensure that they are appropriate and specific to their intended use. Unless required by law or regulation, we will never ask for your social security number.

Due to the technological world we live in and the constant threat to Internet security we can only be held liable for a breach of security if it is due to the negligence of the company and within the control of the company to have prevented it from occurring. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If someone hacks into our site for the purpose of stealing our data, we cannot be held accountable for such action except to prosecute such an individual to the fullest extent that the law provides.If you have any questions about security, please contact us.

**Legal Disclaimer**

In certain situations, Peanut Labs may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Peanut Labs may be required by law to disclose personal information in order to comply with a subpoena, current judicial proceeding, court order, or similar legal process served on our Company or website and when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. In such an event we will notify individuals that such an action has been taken and at the same time divulge such information as has been subpoenaed after conferring with our attorney.

**Business Transfer**

Peanut Labs could choose to sell or transfer part or substantially all of its business assets as part of a private business transaction (e.g., merger, IPO, sale), which could include the market research division, at any time. Any business transaction of this nature would only be to an entity or corporation that agreed to comply with all of the terms and conditions of our privacy policies. Any changes that such a company or entity would make to the privacy provisions of this document would require pre-notification to all respondents of such changes and new intentions regarding the use of the information.

**Links to 3rd party sites**

Our Web site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of PeanutLabs. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

**Testimonials**

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [support@peanutlabs.com](mailto:support@peanutlabs.com).

**Blogs**

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in this area may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, contact us at [support@peanutlabs.com](mailto:support@peanutlabs.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Social Media Features**

Our Web site includes social media features, such as the Facebook and Twitter buttons and widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Disclosure**

Please note that we supply content to other websites who promote surveys. You will always know when Peanut Labs is collecting your information as our privacy policy will be linked from that page. Only aggregated de-identified information is shared with our partners.

**CASRO Code of Standards**

Peanut Labs complies with the Code of Standards followed by the Council of American Survey Research Organizations (CASRO). All the responsibilities and requirements embodied in the Code of Standards for respecting respondents’ rights, reporting to Clients, and ensuring ethical and responsible research practices are followed by Peanut Labs. You may see the CASRO Code of Standards here (<http://www.casro.org/menu-standards.cfm>)

**Changes to this Policy**

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email, sent to the e-mail address specified in your account or by means of a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

For assistance or comments regarding the PeanutLabs.com website or our privacy statement, please contact: [support@peanutlabs.com](mailto:support@peanutlabs.com)

**Address**

180 Montgomery Street, Suite 1700

San Francisco, CA 94104
